we're starting today's episode at the
new installation of the barge i feel
like i'm definitely like bigging up this
new quest thing too much just because
it's taken me so long to make so i've
sort of started everything i've got a
payment chest and i've got some
instructions unfortunately it's still
not ready and that's why i'm worried
that everyone will be too hyped for this
and it won't meet people's expectations
but here we go so
it's gonna cost 250 diamonds each
because i keep adding to the prize pool
grab yourself a partner and sign up for
the ultimate quest you will have to
follow a series of clues and puzzles to
reach the end first with your team the
winner will receive a mega ultimate
prize second place will get something
too now i have started i've done about
three stages so far
and that's about it so team one and
you're not allowed then the signups are
not open yet they're not open but i got
my first clue so team one will start
here team two will start the other one
and they lead in different directions
they'll have to solve an individual clue
and it's all
i really want to take everyone through
it but unfortunately all it would take
is someone to watch this video
and then all of a sudden the whole thing
is spoiled so again it's something i'm
working on but i need to unfortunately
keep it mega secret otherwise the whole
project's kind of spoiled
kind of spoiled but what we are going to
work on today is this the dead space in
the shopping district so i've got myself
a bunch of shulker boxes
full of materials i think i have
everything together
for my design i'm probably gonna run out
of this block mushroom stem
but i think we're pretty much ready to
go i've got a lot of stuff ready and my
plan is to build single-handedly
the mycelium hq i spent two days
designing this thing
and i can't wait to get it in game now
before we get into this design ow
ow
i have to give you fair warning because
it's a little bit strange
um this design
is nothing like i have ever built before
so i just want to say that now
i've never built anything like this ever
before it's a brand new style using very
different blocks to what i'm used to
it's nothing like the original so this
base might be marmite you're either
gonna love it no you're gonna hate it so
i think you've had fair warning
i'd love to get the opinions but let's
get into the time lapse because we need
to start building
this really big mycelium
headquarters
i've eaten my carrot let's go
[Music]
so
okay so the moment of truth
what do you think do you love it
or do you hate it
like i said
this is nothing like i've ever built
before this is an organic build made up
entirely of mushrooms and i wasn't sure
whether i wanted to commit to this
design or not just because one it was
challenging
two
it's something that i've never done
before and three it's definitely the
smurf castle okay this is where the
smurfs live but on the whole i think
from a technical building standpoint it
looks phenomenal whether or not this is
the perfect base for the mycelium
resistance i don't know but i've lent
into the mushroom thing and we've got
ourselves a phenomenal looking
headquarters but of course i want to
know what you think oh dear that doesn't
sound good
that does not sound good at all
okay
that's normal
everything is fine
everything is okay
[Music]
[Laughter]
we have to light this up
quickly
if we don't light this up it's gonna be
a nightmare for anyone that goes in here
maui why are you banging the gong
oh this is such a death trap in here
don't mind me my cat's just banging a
gong
oh we got a disc
this is such a mess i'm gonna die let's
get this lit up and then we can focus on
fixing it okay i think i've taken care
of it so the reason that this place is
an absolute death trap for mob spawning
is obviously because on the mushroom
island mobs don't spawn
hostile mobs don't spawn at all however
we are just off the coast meaning all
the mobs want to spawn anywhere but
there so they choose here so let's
replace the damage a few seconds ago you
just heard the gong go off that was
because every now and again maui likes
to sit on his bed which is right next to
me on the desk and every now and again
he really likes to play with the little
baton thing that you hit the gong with
and every now and again he just he just
sets it off and it's it always catches
me off guard and it's always really
funny so i'm gonna leave that in the
video so you know what i have to go
through
every time i'm recording okay i think
it's pretty i was just about to say that
it's all safe in here and it's totally
not where did you spawn from i feel like
i cannot get enough lights in here so
there we go the mycelium hq is
officially built i'm pretty proud of
this build and i'm kind of looking
forward to seeing what everyone says
about it and i have to say even though i
designed and built this solo the team
actually helped a massively to get
together all the blocks for this so i i
gathered quite a fair amount of it you
know like the the concrete and uh the
terracotta uh all of the other blocks
but they got together and they farmed up
a bunch of the white stem and the
mushroom blocks because i don't know if
you know but this block is pretty unique
the mushroom stem
it's just a bit of a pain
to actually farm so now my goal is to
actually get this in a place where we
can actually have a meeting because
right now
yeah it's not really meetingable that's
not a word but i'm gonna use it we need
a meetingable place
and then when everyone is online i'm
probably gonna make the maybe make the
floor out of brown mushroom i think this
is a good block to use
when everyone's online we're going to
well there's no emergency meeting button
the first thing to do is tell etho we
need a new emergency meeting button and
we should get everyone together and go
over some plans because it's been a bit
disruptive actually since we lost the
original base we've been a little bit
lost so it's time to regroup recalibrate
and figure out our next steps so it's
looking a little bit cleaner in here all
i'm going to do for now is make
ourselves a quick table in the middle
for us to have a temporary meeting place
there we go we've got a table and a big
old chair for mother spore now the only
thing that i feel like i really need to
do in this base before we can have a
meeting and there's definitely not
enough of my team online
in order to have a meeting right now but
the last thing that i want to do is add
of course the mycelium source block i
think it'd be cool just to have it
hanging from the ceiling like this there
we go and we are done i think we've got
enough of a base now to have a proper
meeting this has a very very different
feel to the original base it's more
grungy and kind of dark and sinister
because of i think it's just because of
like the mushroom blocks before it was
made of quartz which makes it seem much
more modern i kind of like it it just
needs
quite a lot of tidying up which i'm
hoping someone will volunteer to do
because i have spent
many hours on this now and there's
something that i desperately want to
show you that i've been working on in
the background so this is where we're
probably going to leave this
headquarters for now until i can get
enough people online to have a little
meeting to discuss our next steps and
also
hopefully someone will make a door
because this is not appropriate so what
i want to show you and i know i've said
this several times that i didn't want to
spoil the barge quest these are the two
things i've got going on in my life at
the moment mycelium headquarters
barge those are the two things so i
actually i have to show you something
pretty cool so i said that i didn't want
to spoil this and i'm not going to read
out the clues and the riddles and stuff
so that they can they can do it ahead of
time but i do want to show you something
really cool i've been working on and i
will request that the hermits don't look
at my video particularly this one if
they don't want spoilers
so one of the clues somewhere along the
line is going to lead you behind my
mansion and if you go behind my mansion
looking very finished if you ask me
you can fly just over here and you see
this white concrete box and it's not
meant to look like anything cool to look
at but this is part of the quest that i
have been working on now this is like
maybe stage four i think of the the
whole quest now what you have to do is
you have to take you and your partner
inside each room so each room is going
to be absolutely identical okay so they
they go in and then they are presented
with a challenge they have to come in
and i have to read the clues so two
words that make up the best shop in the
shopping district and uh i think we all
know which shop that is it's the barge a
quick remembering will lead you to know
that there is both spruce not very much
spruce admittedly
and
dark oak so if you both stand on that or
put an item you open up this door
okay and then it says find the matching
button and press them at the same time
so i'm hoping that they're going to work
together on this and not use the the
items but it is also very possible to
get stuck in here which is hilarious if
they're not careful they will get soft
locked and end up stuck in the dungeon
and i'll have to come and rescue them
and that will cost them
valuable time you may have also noticed
there's a little secret sign there
little secret sign i won't tell you what
it says
so
you have to press the both this button
and the matching button in here at the
same time to open the next door and then
if you go in here there's a lever
press the lever and you open up
this so this is the sort of thing that
i'm working on these little puzzle rooms
to try and get something very unique
going
for the barge quest so that's just the
first room now i actually am having a
bit of trouble figuring out what to do
for this room so i thought okay we've
done a little bit of a brain teaser why
don't i give them a more skill based
challenge and then i thought why not use
the surrounding land to my advantage
gonna do a b dubs now gotta shreep first
try the bed race is no fun when bdubs
isn't online okay so my idea here is
something that i actually need to test
so i'm thinking for this challenge
the door here at the end these two
pistons will be powered blocking the
entrance okay this is the not the reward
but this is going to be the next clue
man this thing is going to be
extremely long i think this is going to
be half an episode and i think if i
hurry up i can have this whole thing
done
by next episode and hopefully we'll get
enough people to sign up and record it
because it's going to be a lot of fun so
here's what i'm thinking for this last
challenge and i
i don't think that the other hermits are
going to watch this video so hopefully
this remains a secret i'm kind of
relying on people not to spoil this
because it's uh if they know how to do
this they're going to breeze through it
and that's that's not really my
intention so i'm thinking this one is a
shooting challenge and i wanted to just
give it a quick test so i'm gonna use
this which is something that i don't
think people use very often so i'm
thinking what i'm gonna do
is place a redstone torch here
and have it power those pistons all the
way over there and i'm going to have
several of these dotted around
and they will have to remove all of them
to remove the power from those pistons
hopefully that makes a bit of sense but
i just need to test whether it's
actually possible
to hit these targets from all the way
over here how challenging is it
come on we got this
i can't actually see
where it ends up oh
there we go
big boom that was amazing that was a
good shot and it did do a little bit of
damage around it
but it didn't destroy the see this is
why we test people look at this the
torch
not destroyed so it may need to be
like this
so that the blast radius actually
catches it and destroys the torch man
i'm so glad i tested this
otherwise we would have ended up with a
absolute failure of a task now i've only
got seven of these things they're quite
expensive to to make so i'm gonna do
three on each side so i've only got two
more to test with can i get this first
time
boom
nailed it and it also nailed the torch
okay that is a really good sign
so one two and then maybe one really a
bit further away like over here i just
need to the problem is i need to make
sure that these are possible so i may
need another another testing
testing one right there we go i probably
could have tested this with something
less expensive than an end crystal i
think they even added target blocks so i
could have done that right so we got
three targets
that we gotta get that's gotta that's
definitely possible right
boom okay wicked it's absolutely
possible so now all i've got to do is
link this up with a bit of redstone
and i think this will be absolutely
perfect so in theory this is what
happens
they destroy the crystal that gets
destroyed and it powers off but they
obviously have to get all three crystals
with their bow and arrow in order to do
this hopefully they won't go and examine
this too hard i'm gonna be here during
the actual thing so you know i'm gonna
be here to tell them two in here two and
here it's gonna be quite a fun
interactive quest where i'm seriously
involved in it
so
yeah they shouldn't touch any of this
stuff right now i'm going to go and copy
all of this stuff over to the other side
and get this part of the quest which is
one of the larger parts i must admit
this is more complicated than i
originally intended but i need to copy
it over to this side
and then i think
the barge quest will be
very close to being finished after a
couple of hours i have completed this
section of the barge quest this is all
you guys are gonna get spoiled you're
gonna have to wait for the next episode
or maybe even the one after that to find
out what happens in the exact thing i've
replicated
hopefully roughly the same locations for
the ender crystals over here so should
be a pretty fair game i've tried to make
each pathway for the two different teams
different but the same difficulty which
is which is always a challenge but
nonetheless we are done here so now it's
time to head back to the shopping
district where i actually had a word
with impulse from the mycelium
resistance team
and he's interested
in the offer i made last episode so
we're gonna go and talk to him and see
what he has to say
oh my goodness
my elytra just broke
at the most convenient time that could
have been terrible
now i put down an offer for a fair
amount of diamonds to try and acquire
this land here because if i can get this
it means the barge can expand quite a
lot because i already own like all this
land around here but not this and not
this so
let's see if impulse is there impulse
impulse
i was just in here checking my latest
profits of this shop man
yeah i've been a customer recently so um
i wanted to talk to you about this offer
right because you sent me a message
saying near one of the chat
yeah i've been i saw this a while ago
i've really been pondering whether or
not i want to accept this it looks like
there's about 90 diamonds in this chest
and i don't know if you noticed but i've
already moved this shop one time this
season
oh so i mean
you would move it for me hmm but i don't
know if there's any you see i got this
spot because it's a prime location which
i think is why you want it right
so close to town hall i want to expand
the barge yeah so i don't know if i'm
willing to
move it again so i was thinking maybe we
could strike a different kind of deal
right now you just saw i'm making a lot
of profits in there i drive a lot of
traffic into this shop
what if my shop was actually inside the
barge
no and then that's the giant guardian
not the giant gun no
no i don't have to build the gun i don't
want to build a guardian again i'm
trying to get out of this
but maybe just a little corner of the
barge that i could just sell my stuff
and then
you know what i mean barge company and
and and partners
okay are you open to partnership make it
make a little impulse corner where you
can buy all your
goods dude i like that i like that i
could even name it impulse buys and i
could put other random stuff on there
maybe
it's too i can't now that you said that
it's too good it's too that impulse buys
that's amazing
i i have loads of space to fill i am
well up for that
if you give me this space i will make
impulse buys a thing
okay excellent let's do it that that's
much better than me rebuilding this and
find another plot i still get the 90
diamonds though right even though we're
partners yeah i guess okay okay
and um for rent do i need to rent the
space from you do i are we am i monthly
fees what do you want to do or something
along the lines profit share we can come
up with something we'll make it work but
i think we're going to be driving some
more traffic into your bargaining that's
amazing i i'm well up for this
so have you also seen what i've done
over yonder with the mycelium
headquarters the brand new one the one
that hasn't been discovered because
everyone knows where it is
already yeah
you've already done something yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah you work fast my friend
oh my goodness i need to show someone
before i explode
okay wow
it's i have not seen
this it's very much ruby oh my gosh
wait that island didn't exist did you
build that entire island i built
everything
so this is what i needed all those
mushroom blocks for
yeah i am super impressed
this is amazing it's huge there's no
interior yet uh i'm hoping to get the
team together and kind of show it all
off
and get get some help on certain things
but uh this is this is what we got so
far this is great man
this is so good and i was i was
wondering
you know kind of what we went through
over in hepland um we kind of got
destroyed and i was wondering like
can we can we defend this this in a
similar
manner
i don't know i mean it's a lot easier to
defend an underground base you think you
need some redstone help
well i mean yeah we got i mean we got
some decent members of the team etho and
i could probably do a lot but uh
protecting the base this size i think we
might need some help
we'll call in the big guns
i think we should i i'm thinking we call
in we call in the
the man himself the man that goes so
overboard that you will never get out of
here alive you know what i mean
there's only one person that can do that
that's for sure yeah we need to i think
we need to call in doc i i think all we
we don't even need to message him right
i'm just thinking we just put a signal
in the sky like batman and he shall come
he shall arrive
exactly if we just leave him some
instructions he's gonna he's gonna make
this place so impenetrable that we don't
even have to worry although we may not
be able to use it ourselves but i think
part of the fun
yeah yeah no one goes over the top like
the goat himself so let's call him in
man all right let's make a let's make
like a hmm a doc symbol or a goat in the
sky
yes that is true here's the goat i think
i think a goat would be a lot easier
okay let's do let's do a goat in the sky
like made out of glass try and try and
make it look like a a signal you ready
okay i'm ready all right let's go i need
get some glass and stuff
[Music]
well i think that
making a giant glass thing uh making a
bat signal not easy not easy at all this
as you probably saw from the time lapse
this messed with my head
so badly because from this angle
it looks correct it looks absolutely
spot-on
from up here
i've got to say
it doesn't look right at all i had to in
my head flip it upside down and
backwards
to get this right and it took several
attempts but in the end
we did it i also thought it looked a bit
weird floating in the air with
absolutely nothing between it so i made
a rather wobbly
beam of light
that slowly spreads over i mean this
isn't gonna hopefully be here forever so
uh it will be removed at some point i'm
sure but look it's the goat signal
it's time for doc
to come and help us defend the
headquarters if he's interested of
course left him a little message
goat we need to protect the resistance
hq will you join us i think that's about
as simple as it gets it's not it's not
very defensible at the moment so
hopefully he's got some i don't know
blaze turrets or some
destruct thing that will destruct the
whole server i
don't know what redstone people do these
days i'm pretty sure what i'm pretty
sure you can make stuff that just
destroys everything
right so that has been it for today's
episode we have had a
choc full episode of barge quest
mycelium headquarters built
goat
and we actually have a partner in the
barge
that was a very unexpected twist i love
the idea of an impulse buy section the
name is amazing i can't turn something
like that down you know i love a good
pun
so there we are
what an episode and i shall see you in
the next one
good
bye